Choyo Matsuta

Home Address 1662 257th Street, #1, Harbor City, CA 90710, USA Cell (714) 875-7913

Email cmatsuta@hotmail.com

Summary

Professional capacity to assist in designing ERP business software systems. Hands on experience in operations using Microsoft ERP system such as Dynamics GP and Dynamics 365 FO, BC and Sales and also implementing Shopify API. Have the necessary expertise to develop business and accounting software to help facilitate the business operations of clients. Will to consult with engineering stuff to evaluate interface between hardware and software, develop specifications and performance requirements and resolve customer problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Japan Business Systems Technology Torrance, CA Sep., 2011 - Current Sr ERP System Consultant / Assistant Manager

- Modify existing software to correct errors, to adapt it to new hardware, or to upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Advise customer about or perform maintenance of software system.
- System implementation and testing.
- Analyze information to determine, recommend, and plan installation of a new system or modification of an existing system.
- Consult with engineering staff to evaluate interface between hardware and software, develop specifications and performance requirements, or resolve customer problems.
- Store, retrieve, and manipulate data for analysis of system capabilities and requirements.
- Consult with customers or other departments on project status, proposals, or technical issues, such as software system design or maintenance.
- Coordinate installation of software system.
- Prepare reports or correspondence concerning project specifications, activities, or status.
- Train users to use new or modified equipment.
- Evaluate factors such as reporting formats required, cost constraints, or need for security restrictions to determine hardware configuration.
- Project management and project leading.
- Work with developers to build apps and business intelligence report by Power platform.

Calsoft Systems, Torrance, CA Nov., 2009 - Sep., 2011

Accounting Operation Support

- Assisted internal accounting and operation tasks.
- Assisted manager with closing process and prepared monthly Work in Progress reports.
- Provided high quality helpdesk support by troubleshoot telephonically or emailing with customers in both English and Japanese and document help desk requests and resolutions.
- Create or revise user instructions, procedures, or manuals.
- Prepared training and workflow documentations.
- Test developed software.

TourMation Inc., Torrance, CA, Aug., 2008 - Aug., 2009

Accounting Support

- Provided on-site daily accounting support.
- Worked within project team to assist developing and overseeing software system testing and validation procedures.
- Consult with customers or other departments on project status, proposals and technical issues such as software system design and maintenance.
- Assisted development of documentation
- Effective communication and advise customer about and regulate the maintenance of software system.

EDUCATION

UCR Extension Web development, July 2020 - Current

Activities and Societies: The Coding Boot Camp at UCR Extension covers a full-stack curriculum, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, and more.

Major: Accounting

California State University, Fullerton, CA

Bachelor of Science - Business Administration, May 2006

Grossmont College, El Cajon, CA

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Business Finance; Advanced Business Communication; Marketing; Interpersonal Communication; Organizational Behavior; Strategic Management; The International Economy; Computer Information System; Business Law

RECOGNITIONS

Recognized as an outstanding CSUF student July 2006.

SKILLS

Languages:

Speak, read and write English and Japanese

Other:

Active communication skills

Ability to interact with a wide variety of cultures

Teamwork and ability to relate to and lead people

Motivate, hardworking, and reliable

Ability to contribute and convey thoughts and ideas to others effectively

Able to adapt to change

Qualifications Summary

Microsoft Dynamics AX Financials, Microsoft Dynamics AX Trade and Logistics, Microsoft Dynamics GP Integration Manager, Microsoft Dynamics GP Financials